# OGAMBA PATRICK JUNIOR

Software Engineer, Mobile Developer, FullStack Developer

### Contact

#### Address:

Carrefour Nouvelle Route Cite Sic, Douala, Cameroon

#### **Phone Number:**

+ 237 670157564

#### **Email:**

ogambapatrickjunior@gmail.com

### Languages

- English
- French

# Education

#### **Software Engineering**

 University Institute of the Gulf of Guinea (IUG).

### Socials

#### **MY PORTFOLIO**

patrick-junior.onrender.com

#### **GITHUB**

- PatrickJunior007

#### **LINKEDIN**

Patrick Junior

### Certifications

- Bachelor Degree in Software Engineering.
- Higher National Diploma (HND) in Software Engineering.

# Summary

Software Engineer with three years of experience, I successfully combined my studies, job and other commitments showing myself to be self-motivated, organized and capable of working in collaboration with others. In addition to that I'm very hardworking, learn quickly and easily.

# Skills Highlights

### Software Engineer 09/2020 till present

- Have skills in Graphic Designing.
- Experienced in modeling of applications.
- Well-versed in web development tools including HTML, CSS, JQuery, WordPress, Bootstrap and Tailwind CSS.
- Experienced in Search Engine Optimization (SEO).
- Skilled in programming languages such as PHP, JAVA, SQL, and JavaScript.
- Skilled in React Native, React, Next Js and Vue/Nuxt Js Frameworks.
- Clear and understanding knowledge in the versioning tools Git and GitHub.
- Skilled in web application and REST APIs development with SpringBoot and Laravel.
- Other Skills: Node, Express, MongoDB, FireBase, TypeScript, Testing, Cucumber, Cypress.

## Experience

#### **Software Engineer** (24/07/2023 – Present)

- ADAA, Douala Cameroon
  - Development of both web and mobile applications using the latest technologies of React, Next Js, Tailwind CSS,
     TypeScript and React Native.
  - Responsible for the development and Integration of RESTFUL APIs for the backend of projects using Laravel.
  - Modeling, documenting and design the technical architecture of each of the projects within the company.
  - Maintain and ensure the proper functioning and continuity of various web and mobile applications following the main guidelines.
  - Organize and execute functional and security tests on the different modules, both web and mobile solutions.
  - Collaboration with UI/UX designers to improve user interfaces and designs.

#### **Software Engineer** (01/03/2022 – 23/07/2023)

- NKAP SARL, Douala Cameroon
  - Worked on several web applications using technologies like Nuxt/Vue JS, React, PHP, Laravel and WordPress.
  - Development of mobile applications using React Native,
     TypeScript, Expo RN, REST APIs and Firebase.

- Took part in testing and automating web applications and software using technologies like Cypress and Cucumber.
- Integration of **RESTFUL APIs** in both web and mobile applications.
- Worked on the **SEO** of several clients' websites.
- Collaboration with UI/UX designers to improve user

### Frontend Developer (19/09/2021 – 29/12/2021)

- SIKATRONIC GROUP, Douala Cameroon
  - Using technologies like **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript** and **Bootstrap**.
  - Collaboration with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability, experience and design.

### **Intern** (19/09/2020 – 19/01/2021)

- 237SOFT, Douala Cameroon
  - Took part into projects connected with both Web app, App development and Modeling.